COLT MCANLIS: 随着外界的大量手持设备
COLT MCANLIS: With a plethora of handhelds out in the wild,
现在是良好的时机来扩展你的用户
now is the perfect time to start extending your users'
手持设备体验到穿戴设备上了
handheld experience to their wearable device.
我是Colt McAnlis
My name is Colt McAnlis.
手持设备和穿戴设备交流的第一步
The first step to communicating between your handheld
始于穿戴设备DataLayer API
and your wearable starts with a wearable data layer API.
它的核心是  DataLayer API允许你的手持设备
At its core, the data layer API allows for your handheld
和穿戴设备在任意时间自动同步每一块
and wearable to automatically sync a piece of data any time
更改的数据
it's changed.
酷的地方就是  所有繁重的任务
The cool part is, that all the heavy lifting
像蓝牙协商和数据传输
to make that happen-- like Bluetooth negotiation and data
都会在DataLayer API下处理
transfer-- is handled under the hood,
解放你并让你去处理更重要的事
freeing you up to work on more important things.
这个过程的工作原理是你允许你的设备
This process works by allowing your devices
担当数据发送者  数据接收者  或者两者都是
to take on the row of data sender, data receiver, or both.
发送方设备创建一块将被同步的数据块
The sender device sets up a piece of data to be synced.
一旦数据发生改变就会被发送到接收方设备
And any time that data changes, it will be sent over to the receiver.
接收方设备  相反的  监听数据更改
The receiving device, in turn, listens for changes
提供一个回调函数来提醒APP
and provides a callback function to notify the app
当某些东西更新的时候
when something's been updated.
核心对象将被当成DataItem在设备间传送
The core object that's sent between the devices
这有效地在设备上提供了
is known as DataItem, which effectively provides
能够在手持设备和穿戴设备间
data storage on the device, with automatic syncing
自动同步数据仓库
between the handheld and the wearable.
在基础上  DataItem被认为是有效载荷对象
At its base, DataItem consists of a payload object,
它将持有真实的数据  而路径对象则是为
which will hold the actual data, as well as a path object that
DataItem扮演唯一的标识字符串
acts as a unique identifier string for this data
这对数据接收方很重要
item, which is important on the receiver side,
也是为了知道某些特定的数据块是否真正被更新了
to know which particular piece of data has actually been updated.
DataItem对于在手持设备和穿戴设备之间
DataItem is great for sending small batches of data back
来回发送小批量的数据很有优势
and forth between the wearable and handheld.
举个例子  用穿戴设备传感器
For example, using the wear device sensors
来收集心率信息然后通过用户的
to gather heart rate information and then send it
手机发送  这将会与过去14周的
across the user's phone, which will then cross-reference it
传感器数据交叉引用
with the past 14 weeks of sensor data,
然后提供结果图到手表上来显示
and provide the resulting graph back to display it on the watch.
作为当前的限制  DataItem对象的负载
As a current restriction, the payload of a data item object
是设计于处理小量数据的  大概100K左右吧
is designed to handle small amounts of data, say around 100K or so.
如果你想让这些更强大
So if you want something more powerful,
你需要一个asset对象附加到DataItem上
you need to attach an asset object to the data item.
这允许你通过蓝牙传输发送大块的
This allows you to send large blobs of binary data
二进制数据  像图片
over Bluetooth transport, like images.
举个例子  假如手持设备APP
For example, let's say the handheld app
下载了一张图片  调整了大小并把它发送到
downloaded an image, resized it, and sent it over
穿戴设备来显示
to the wearable for display.
手持设备在过程中处理了所有繁重的工作
The handheld handles all the heavy lifting in processing,
然后穿戴设备用来显示工作的简单结果
while the wear device gets to display the simple results of it.
关于asset对象酷的地方在于他们处理了数据的缓存
The cool thing about asset objects is that they handle caching of data
以防止数据重传和节省蓝牙带宽
to prevent retransmission and conserve Bluetooth bandwidth,
意思是这里只能有一个asset对象的实例被缓存
meaning there can be only one instance of an asset cached.
如果你尝试多次发送它
And if you try to send it multiple times,
它将不会浪费带宽和电源
it won't waste bandwidth or battery.
简单地说  DataLayer API
On the simpler side of things, the data layer API
同时提供了Message API
also provides the message API, which
这是用于做普通任务的API  像告诉你的穿戴设备
are ideal to do common tasks like telling your wear
开启一个Activity  或者是告诉手机
device to start an activity, or telling the phone
切歌
to skip to the next song.
默认地  这些消息通常是
By default, these messages are generally
远程过程调用的性质
of the remote procedure call nature.
也就是说  一旦它们被发送
That is, once they're shipped off,
消息是否被收到将无从考证
there's no validation that the message was actually received.
如果你想要发送一些更复杂的东西  你可以设置这些消息
If you want something more complex, however, you can set the messages
工作在  请求/回应  模型里
to work in request/response model, where
连接的一方将发送
one side of the connection will send
一条消息到另一个设备  其中  反过来  接收方将做一些工作
a message to the other device, which, in turn, does some work,
然后进行响应  反过来  和这些响应
and then responds, in turn, with the response.
最酷的用例是你将要看到的
The coolest use cases are the one that you have yet to come up with.
为了开始  请翻阅API页面
To get started, swing by the API page,
这里将包含所有你需要开始同步设备的信息
which will contain all the info you need to start syncing devices.
同时别忘记查看Android Developer主页
And don't forget to check out the Android Developer home
以获得更多有用的建议和技巧
page for more great tips and tricks.
拥有这个更强大的Data API
With these more powerful data APIs,
你将有新的机会使你的设备能够
there's new opportunities to get your devices
用新的  有趣的方式在一起工作
working with each other in new and interesting ways.
我的名字是Colt McAnlis
My name is Colt McAnlis.
现在  去创建更好的APP吧
Now go build better apps.